Inspector Tsunemori, take
Masaoka and go look for Kogami.
常守監視官
征陸を連れて狡噛を捜せ
Kagari, Kunizuka, and I
俺と縢　六合塚は
will divide up and look for the source
of the jamming and destroy it.
手分けして妨害電波の発信源を捜し出しつぶす
Okay.
はい
To be honest, I have
no idea what's going on at all.
正直　何が何だかさっぱりだ
Strong jamming, an underground
area that our records say doesn't exist...
強力なジャミングに
記録にない地下空間
...and a request for
reinforcements from Kogami...
狡噛からの応援要請
Well, one thing we can say for
sure is that this is pretty serious.
ただ事じゃないのは間違いないっすよ
お前もそう思うか
You think so, too?
I've never heard Ko speak like that before.
コウちゃんのあんな声 初めて聞きました
He really did sound desperate.
マジで切羽詰まってた
My head is overflowing with thoughts
I can't allow anyone to know about
誰にも見せられないもの
脑海里充斥着的喧嚣
頭の中溢れて
谁都无法看见
I've strayed into a world void of even mistakes
間違いさえも無い世界へ
我在这个不会犯错的机械世界里
迷い込んでる
一路行走一路彷徨
It's being rubbed in so deep it's hard to believe
あり得ないほど擦り込まれてる
与你擦肩而过的次数多到近乎异常
This "world" that holds
only what the eye can see
目に見えるものだけの“世界”現象
我眼里能看到的 就是我全部的世界
Can I flush out the truth?
暴きだせるかな
能否打破它
Plastic Tac Tic,
no one can go crazy anymore
Plastic Tac Tic
plastic tac tic
もう誰もおかしくなれないよ
所有人都习以为常
You, too, are in a plastic beautiful world
貴様もplastic beautiful world
你也一样 plastic beautiful world
In a world with too much beauty,
for some reason I can't see the light
美しすぎる世界に
在这个过于完美的世界里
僕はなぜか
我为什么
光が見えなくて
看不到光明的方向
My bursting heart is an eternal reflection
破裂していく心が
心在一步步碎裂
無限のリフレクション
回音无限
Secret remains for you
secret remains for you
为你留下这个秘密
Don't expose these false colors and futures
見せかけの色と
徒有其表的鲜艳色彩及未来
未来を暴かないで
别打破它
fake's plastic world
keep it secret motion
就让这个秘密继续秘密下去
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:草泥马 TMR@10 校对:西西   后期:时末
# 11 Saint's Supper
What's with all the sneaking around?
何をこそこそやっている
So they're trying to ruin my fun, huh?
邪魔が入ったか
This must be it!
こいつか
Take this!
User authentication, Enforcer Shinya Kogami.
「ユーザー認証 狡噛慎也執行官」
You are a valid user.
「適正ユーザーです」
Target's Threat Judgment
has been updated.
「対象の脅威判定が更新されました」
Enforcement mode is Destroy Decomposer.
「執行モード デストロイ·デコンポーザー」
「対象を完全排除します」
Target will be completely eliminated.
Please be careful.
「ご注意ください」
His appearance...
silence after every two shots...
あの外観
２発ごとの空白
The enemy's weapon must
be a double-barreled hunting gun.
敵の武器は　二連銃身の猟銃か
Unfortunately, your time is up.
残念ながら　時間切れです
The jamming has been broken.
妨害電波が破られました
Soon the main unit
of the MWPSB will rush in.
間もなく公安局の本隊が駆け付けるでしょう
Lovecraft was taken out.
It was shot and destroyed.
ラヴクラフトがやられた
撃たれて壊されたんだ
He finally started shooting back.
やつはとうとう撃ち返してきた
Mr. Senguji?
泉宮寺さん…
When I was young,
昔は発展途上国のインフラ設備に関わる工事が多くてね
I often took part in construction work
on infrastructure in developing countries.
The more dangerous the place was,
the more money I earned.
危険な現場ほど金になった
Conflicts often occurred suddenly,
紛争は突発的で
and there was a limit to our ability
to predict scenarios and manage risk.
状況予測と危機管理には限界があった
There was a time we were attacked
by guerillas in one of those countries.
現地でゲリラの襲撃に遭ったことがある
I think it was at least 70-80 years ago.
もう７０～８０年は前かな
Then, too, the colleague
sitting next to me was shot.
あのときも隣にいた同僚が撃たれたんだ
My friend, who had been crying
and shouting just a moment earlier,
それまで泣いたり叫んだりしていた友人が
had now turned into
nothing but a lump of flesh.
次の瞬間には肉の塊になっていた
His blood splattered
and dripped down my head,
私は飛び散った血しぶきを頭から浴びてね
and his smell stuck to my entire body.
彼の臭いが私の全身にべっとりとこびり付いて
I don't want you to get the wrong idea,
but for me that was a good memory.
勘違いしないでほしいが これはいい思い出の話だ
That time, I felt alive... I felt really alive...
あのときほど命を生きているという実感を痛烈に感じたことはない
I felt it more strongly than I have
ever felt in my entire life.
However, I'm experiencing
that feeling once again right now.
それを今 私は再び味わっている
Once again, the blood has been set
afire in this mechanical heart of mine.
この機械仕掛けの心臓に熱い血のたぎりが蘇っている
And now, you're telling me to run?
ここで逃げろだって
That would be cruel.
それは残酷というものだよ
But from here on, it won't be just a game.
ここから先はゲームでは済みませんよ
That's exactly right.
そのとおりだ
As a hunter, I've shot down lots of
prey over the course of many years.
これまでハンターとして多くの獲物を仕留めてきた
But now, I want to confront
that man as a duelist.
しかし今は　デュエリストとしてあの男と対峙したい
Makishima...
槙島君 君とてまさかここで私が尻尾を巻くさまを見たくて
Surely you didn't muck around with
my game to see me turn tail here, did you?
妙な小細工を弄したわけでもあるまい
You're exactly right.
仰せの通りです あなたの命の輝き
I'll see your life's splendor until the very end.
最後まで見届けさせてもらいます
It'll soon be checkmate for you, Enforcer.
チェックメートが近いぞ　執行官
Crime Coefficient is 328.
He is a target for enforcement action.
「犯罪係数　３２８」
「執行対象です」
Amazing... We did it!
すごい…やったよ
We won!
私たち勝ったよ
I'm sorry... for having
you do something so reckless.
すまん　無茶をさせたな
Once you get out of here,
receive therapy treatment right away.
ここを出たら すぐにセラピーを受けろ
You saw... too many things
that you shouldn't have.
あんたは見るべきじゃないものを見過ぎちまってる
That's okay. You were wonderful, Mr. Kogami.
いいよ 狡噛さん　すてきだったもん
I almost want to become a latent criminal, too.
私も潜在犯になっちゃいたいぐらいだよ
Don't be stupid!
バカを…
Stop it!
やめて　放して
Let me go!
I would very much like for us to talk
all night, but you don't seem very well.
君と語り明かしたいのはやまやまだが
今は具合が悪そうだね
I'll see you again some other time.
いずれまた会おう
Stop it!
やめて狡噛さん
Mr. Kogami!
Don't let your guard down!
油断するな きな臭いなんてもんじゃないぞ
To call this suspicious is
an understatement!
I see bullet holes everywhere.
あちこちに弾痕が
It must be a shotgun.
散弾だな
I haven't seen traces from a gun
that uses gunpowder for a long time.
火薬を使った銃の痕跡なんて久しぶりだ
Mr. Masaoka!
征陸さん…
Mr. Kogami...
狡噛さん…
Someone!
誰か
Yuki?!
ゆき！
What was that voice?
今の声は
I think it's the voice of
my friend who went missing!
行方が分からなくなってた私の友人の声だと思います
Mr. Kogami?!
狡噛さん
Mr. Kogami!
This is terrible...
ひでぇな…
He got shot in several places.
あちこちにもらってるじゃねえか
Missy! Can you administer first aid?!
嬢ちゃん　応急処置は
I've had training on it several times,
訓練だけは何度も…
but I've never actually done it.
でも 実際にやったことはなくて…
Then, leave it to me.
なら　俺に任せとけ
What is it?
There's one more person.
もう一人いる…
He took your friend away.
お前のダチを連れてった…
Step aside, missy.
どいてろ　嬢ちゃん
In any event, we have to stop his bleeding.
とにかく血止めなきゃ
Ah!
What're you thinking?! Inspector!
何考えてるんだ 監視官
The case isn't over yet!
まだ事件が終わってないんです
Dammit!
くそっ
This place is like a battlefield... no,
an execution ground...
まるで戦場… いや　処刑場だ
こりゃ ３人や４人なんてもんじゃない
It couldn't have been just three or four people...
Several dozen people... no...
数十人…いや
in the worst-case scenario, close to
one hundred people must have died here.
下手したら１００人近く死んでますよね
Kogami was lured in here.
ここに狡噛が誘い込まれた
Mass murder... A massacre?
大量殺人　虐殺 犯人の目的は
What could the culprit's goal be?
A game, maybe?
ゲームじゃないっすか
What?
Er... Well, ever since we came
down here, I've been feeling...
いや この地下にやって来たときからずっと感じてたんすよ
...that this place looks like the kind of
battle arena you see in fighting games.
対戦ゲームのステージみたいだなって…
I could understand if it was virtual,
バーチャルならともかく 生きた人間を使ってゲームだと
but playing a game
using live human beings?!
This is Hound 1
Can someone hear me?!
こちらハウンド１ 誰か聞こえるか
This is Shepherd 1.
What's the status there?
こちらシェパード１ 状況は
I took Hound 3 into my care.
ハウンド３を保護した
He's hurt so bad that
I'm surprised he's still alive.
生きているのが不思議なありさまだ
The culprit is still on the run with a hostage.
犯人は人質をとって依然逃走中
Shepherd 2 is pursuing the culprit
all by herself. Please hurry!
シェパード２が単独で追跡を続行している
急いでくれ
Dammit! Got it.
くそっ 了解した
Don't go anywhere. We'll head
there to assist you right away!
その場を動くな すぐに救援に向かう
どうやらそのくそったれなゲームとやらは
Sounds like that damn so-called game...
...isn't over yet.
まだ終わっていないらしいな
My body feels heavy.
体が重い
自分の体じゃないみたいだ
It doesn't feel like my own body.
The bullets are still in your body, so...
弾はまだ抜いてねえからな
If I nervously try to pull
them out and hurt an artery,
俺がおっかなびっくりやって
太い血管を傷つけたら本当に致命傷だ
it really will become fatal.
Have the pros work on it
after we get you out of here.
搬送後　プロにやってもらえ
Where's Inspector Tsunemori?
常守監視官はどこに
That's what I'd like to know.
She went rushing off.
こっちが聞きてえよ
突っ走っていった 誰かを追っていったみたいだ
It seemed like she was chasing someone.
Your first aid is finished
so I'll go after missy right away.
お前の応急処置が終わったから
俺も今すぐ嬢ちゃんを追い掛ける
I'm coming, too.
俺も行く
Are you an idiot?
お前はアホか
だが…
But!
Sorry to do that
when you're seriously injured.
悪いな　重傷だってのに
But I don't wanna waste any more time.
でもな　これ以上時間の無駄は嫌なんだよ
Even you got hurt this badly.
お前がこんなになるんだ
はっきり言って嬢ちゃんもかなりヤバい
Frankly, missy is in huge danger.
Enforcer Masaoka!
征陸執行官
Good timing! Inspector!
ちょうどよかった 監視官
Hold down Kogami
so that he won't move.
狡噛が動かないように押さえ付けといてくれ
You sure are tenacious... seriously...
しぶといもんだな　まったく
What is it?
何だ
It seems like Ko shot someone.
コウちゃんが1人撃ったみたいっすね
Toyohisa Senguji?!
泉宮寺豊久
Senguji, you said?!
泉宮寺だと
誰っすかそれ
Who's that?
You don't even check the Ministry
of Welfare's recommended news?
厚生省の推薦ニュースも見てないの
Why would I watch that crap?!
見てねえよそんなもん
Stop right there!
止まりなさい
公安局です 武器を捨てて投降しなさい
This is the MWPSB!
Drop your weapon and surrender!
「犯罪係数　７９」
Crime Coefficient is 79.
Not a target for enforcement action.
「執行対象ではありません」
Trigger will be locked.
「トリガーをロックします」
Akane!
朱
Just hold on, Yuki! I'll rescue you now!
待っててゆき 今助けるから
Oh, I know your face.
ああ　君の顔は知っている
You're Inspector Akane Tsunemori
from the MWPSB... right?
公安局の常守朱監視官だね
So you're the one who
dragged Yuki into this. How dare you!
あなたがゆきを巻き込んだのね　よくも…
I'm Shogo Makishima.
僕は槙島聖護
What?! Makishima?
槙島
I see. So you react to my name, huh?
なるほど そこで驚くのか
Just as you'd expect from the MWPSB.
さすが公安局だ
So you guys had at
least some lead on me.
尻尾ぐらいはつかまれていたというわけか
We've got serious charges
against you on multiple crimes.
あなたには複数の犯罪について重大な嫌疑が掛かっています
Based on the Citizen's Charter,
I demand that you come with me!
市民憲章に基づいて同行を要請します
If you need to talk to me,
then let's do it right here, right now.
話があるならこの場で済まそう
We're both busy people, right?
お互い多忙な身の上だろ
You think you can escape?
逃げられると思ってるの
In order to buy some time
until your reinforcements arrive,
君は応援が来るまでの時間稼ぎのためにも
ここで僕との会話を弾ませるべきじゃないかね
shouldn't you make our conversation lively?
I'm sure an experienced detective
would make that determination.
熟練の刑事ならそう判断するはずだが…
When you said "multiple crimes,"
which were you referring to?
君が言う「複数の犯罪」とはどれのことだろう
Masatake Mido? Or, Rikako Ouryou?
御堂将剛
それとも王陵璃華子
I knew it...
やっぱり…
I think that there's value in people
only when they act based on their will.
僕はね　人は自らの意思に基づいて行動したときのみ
価値を持つと思っている
So I've asked many people
about their suppressed free will
だから　様々な人間に秘めたる意思を問いただし
and observed their actions all this time.
その行いを観察してきた
Don't be so full of yourself!
You're just a criminal!
いい気にならないで
あなたはただの犯罪者よ
How do you define crime to start with?
そもそも何をもって犯罪と定義するんだ
That Dominator you're holding...
君が手にしたその銃
Does the Sibyl System
that governs that gun decide it?
ドミネーターをつかさどるシビュラシステムが決めるのか
「犯罪係数　アンダー５０」
Crime Coefficient is under 50.
Not a target for enforcement action.
「執行対象ではありません」
Trigger will be locked.
「トリガーをロックします」
By analyzing a bio-organism's
force field read by a cymatic scan,
サイマティックスキャンで読み取った生体力場を解析し
they figure out how a person's mind works.
人の心の在り方を解き明かす
The intelligence of science finally
uncovered the secret of souls,
科学の英知はついに魂の秘密を暴くに至り
and this society changed drastically.
この社会は激変した
だが　その判定には人の意思が介在しない
However, people's wills are
not a part of that assessment.
君たちはいったい何を基準に
I wonder just what sort of criteria you
use to divide people into good and evil.
善と悪をより分けているんだろうね
What on earth...
あなた　いったい…
I want to see the splendor of people's souls.
僕は人の魂の輝きが見たい
I want to check and
see if it really is precious.
それが本当に尊いものだと確かめたい
However, when humans base
their lives around Sybil's Oracle,
だが 己の意思を問うこともせず
ただシビュラの神託のままに生きる人間たちに
without ever consulting their own wills,
do they really hold any value?
果たして　価値はあるんだろうか
Well, while I'm here...
せっかくだ 君にも問うてみるとしよう
I guess I'll try testing you, too...
...to assess your judgment
and actions as a detective.
刑事としての判断と行動を
Wh... What are you going to do?!
なっ…何をするつもり
I'm going to kill this woman,
Yuki Funahara...
今からこの女船原ゆきを殺してみせよう
What?!
...right before your eyes.
君の目の前で
Crime Coefficient is 48.
Not a target for enforcement action.
「犯罪係数　４８」
「執行対象ではありません」
Trigger will be locked.
「トリガーをロックします」
止めたければ
If you want to stop me, instead of
using that useless piece of scrap iron,
そんな役に立たない鉄くずではなく
you can pick up the
gun I just gave you and use it.
今あげた銃を拾って使うといい
引き金を引けば弾は出る
If you pull the trigger,
a bullet will come out.
で…できるわけない
Th-There's no way
I can do it, because you are...
だって　あなたは…
Because I'm a good civilian?
善良な市民だからかね
Because Sibyl decided so?
シビュラがそう判定したから
Crime Coefficient is 32.
Not a target for enforcement action.
「犯罪係数　３２」
「執行対象ではありません」
「トリガーをロックします」
- Trigger will be locked.
- Wh-Why?!
ど…どうして
なぜかは僕にも分からない
I don't know why, either.
I've been wondering
about it since my childhood.
子供のころから不思議だったよ
My Psycho-Pass has
always been pure white.
僕のサイコパスはいつだって真っ白だった
ただの一度も曇ったことがない
It never got clouded, not even once.
この体のありとあらゆる生体反応が
All sorts of vital reactions
in my body must be affirming me...
僕という人間を肯定しているんだろうね
...thinking that my actions are those
of one who is sound and good.
これは健やかにして善なる人の行いだと
やめて…
Stop it!
助けて　朱
Help! Akane!
Yuki!
ゆき
You guys can't measure my sins.
君たちでは僕の罪をはかれない
If there is someone who can judge me,
僕を裁ける者がいるとしたら
it'd only be those...
それは…
自らの意思で人殺しになれる者だけさ
...who can become a
killer based on their own will.
今すぐゆきを解放しなさい
Let Yuki go now!
Or...
さもないと…
Or I'll be killed... by your intent to kill.
さもなければ僕は殺される
君の殺意によってね
それはそれで尊い結末だ
That'd be a precious ending in its own way.
Now, you feel the importance
of life in your index finger, don't you?
ほら　人さし指に命の重みを感じるだろう
As long as you're a puppet of Sibyl,
you can never experience that.
シビュラの傀儡でいる限りは決して味わえない
That's the weight of decision and free will.
それが決断と意思の重さだよ
Crime Coefficient is under 20.
Not a target for enforcement action.
「犯罪係数　アンダー２０」
「執行対象ではありません」
Trigger will be locked.
「トリガーをロックします」
デカルトは
Descartes said that those who
can't make a decision can't do so
「決断ができない人間は欲望が大き過ぎるか 悟性が足りないのだ」と言った
because either their desires
are too great, or they lack intellect.
What's wrong? Unless you hold it firmly,
the bullet will miss me.
どうした
ちゃんと構えないと弾が外れるよ
Now, aim at me with the intention to kill.
さあ　殺す気で狙え
あっ…朱
Akane...
残念だ とても残念だよ常守朱監視官
How regrettable. How very regrettable,
Inspector Akane Tsunemori.
No!
嫌っ 助けて
Help!
朱
Akane!
You disappointed me.
君は僕を失望させた
So I have to give you a punishment.
だから 罰を与えなくてはならない
やめて…お願い
Don't...
Please!
Regret your helplessness
and feel despair.
己の無力さを後悔し絶望するがいい
「犯罪係数　０」
Crime Coefficient is 0.
Not a target for enforcement action.
「執行対象ではありませんトリガーを…」
Trigger will be locked.
やめてーっ
Stop it!
Missy?!
お嬢ちゃん
You've come to?
気が付いたか
常守監視官は
Where's Inspector Tsunemori?
I let Yuki die without doing anything...
私がゆきを見殺しにした
何があった
What happened?
I met...
あの男と　会いました
...that man.
That man?
あの男
Shogo Makishima...
槙島聖護は
...can't be judged...
ドミネーターで裁けません…
...by the Dominator!
御伽話（フェアリーテイル）は
童话般的美好
Looks like the fairy tale
died a moment ago
さっき死んだみたい
在刚刚已经死去
煉瓦の病棟で
瓦墙下的病房
In a hospital ward made of bricks,
I found it hard to sing
うまく歌えなくて
在这里我无法歌唱
霧に煙る夜
灰灰蒙蒙的夜
Red moon, come out on this foggy night
浮かべ赤い月
悬浮飘红的月
ほらみて　私を
快 看我
Now look at me, don't avert your gaze
目を逸らさないで
别移开你的视线
黒い鉄格子の中で
黑黑的铁栅背后
I was born behind black iron bars
私は生まれてきたんだ
我来到这个世界
悪意の代償を願え
祈祷恶的代价
Wish for payback for the evil done
望むがままにお前に
如你所愿给你吧
As you wish, I'll give you your justice
さあ与えよう正義を
给与你
壊して　壊される前に
破坏掉正义 在自身毁灭之前
Before you destroy and get destroyed
因果の代償を払い
付出因果的代价
Pay karma's price and have your revenge,
報いよ名もな怪物
因果报应 无名怪兽
Monster without even a name
黒い雨　降らせこの空
黑黑的雨 天空中降落
Make the sky pour down black rain
私は望まれないもの
被流放抛弃的我
I'm not wanted
ひび割れたノイローゼ
神经撕裂般的痛
I cracked and had a breakdown
愛す同罪の傍観者に
你我同罪 爱着的边缘人物
To my beloved partners
in crime looking on
さあ　今ふるえ正義を
拥抱这颤抖的正义
Now exhibit your justice
消せない傷を抱きしめて
抹不掉的伤痕
Treasuring those permanent scars
この身体を受け入れ
接受这残破的身躯
I'll accept this
body and go together with you,
共に行こう
一起走吧
名前のない怪物
无名怪兽
Monster without a name
A world where humans' state of mind and the tendency of their
personalities can be quantified. While all sorts of inclinations
are recorded and policed, these measured numbers
used to judge people's souls are commonly called "Psycho-Pass."
This story is fiction.
The names of all individuals and organizations that appear in the show
are fictitious and have no relation to those in existence in the real world.